Jensen, Vernon Longshore Research Files /4067
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Vernon Jensen Longshore Research Files
1919-1978
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jensen, Vernon.
/4067
24 cubic feet
24 linear ft.
Records (documents).
3085531
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 03, 2011
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, September 26, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Vernon Jensen (July 10, 1907 September 27, 1998) was a founding faculty member of Cornell's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A graduate of Brigham Young University (BS '32), Jensen worked as a substitute teacher in Salt Lake City after college before leaving to pursue graduate study at the University of California at Berkeley (PhD '39). Shortly before completing his degree, Jensen began teaching at the University of Colorado. He taught at UC from 1937 to 1946, during which time he also served as a consultant to the National Defense Mediation Board (1941) and a public panel member, mediator and arbitrator for the National War Labor Board (1942) and Wage Stabilization Director of the NWLB's Ninth Region (1942-1944).
Jensen was among the founding faculty of the School of Industrial and Labor Relations, joining Cornell in 1946. Jensen became Associate Dean of the ILR School in 1965 and was elected to Cornell's Board of Trustees in 1973. In addition to numerous articles, Jensen wrote four books, Lumber and Labor (1945), Heritage of Conflict (1950), Collective Bargaining in the Nonferrous Metal Industry (1955), and Hiring of Dockworkers and Employment Practices in the Ports of New York, London, Liverpool, Rotterdam, and Marseilles (1964).
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor Vernon Jensen: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/18668
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3002: Vernon Jensen Papers /4007: Vernon Jensen Additional Records /4096: Vernon H. Jensen Additional Research and Office Files /4128: Vernon Jensen Additional Papers /4137: Vernon Jensen Additional Files 5839: Vernon Jenson Additional Arbitration Files 5902: Vernon Jensen Additional Arbitration Files /4128 AV: Vernon Jensen Audio-Visual Materials
Stevedores -- United States; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations -- Faculty
3085531
- Misc. Labor Papers, 1919-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- NY Times Articles, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Various Articles 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1951 Folder #1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1951 Folder #2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Longshore Industry Work Storage, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Public Hearing IV, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Waterfront Commission of New York, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Conventions of 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Waterfront News, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Newspaper Articles 1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- New York Herald Tribune 1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Various New York Newspapers, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Waterfront, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Conference Committee's, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Conference Committee's #2, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Conference Committee's #3, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- International Longshoreman's Association, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Citizens' Waterfront Committee, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 1956 Negotiations (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 1956 Negotiations #2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Board of Inquiry on Longshore Industry Work Shortage, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 1956 Negotiations #3 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Labor Disputes Affecting the Maritime Industry of the United States Folder #1, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Labor Disputes Affecting the Maritime Industry of the United States Folder #2, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 1956 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- "A Proposal for Three Years of Industrial Peace", 1956 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- F. Rudge, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- N.Y. Times and N.Y. Herald Tribune Articles Folder #1, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- N.Y. Times and N.Y. Herald Tribune Articles Folder #2, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Interviews, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- I.L.A., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Waterfront News Articles, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Case Study of Government Intervention, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Comparison of Contractual Working Conditions Between Various Shipping Associations and Affiliated Locals of the I.L.A, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- 1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Employers Demands Checkers and Clerks Agreement, 1959-1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- N.Y. Times, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Information Bulletin, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- 1959 Negotiations (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 1959 Negotiations #2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- 1959 Negotiations #3 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Misc. Documents of 1959 Negotiations (Box 3, Folder 13)
- I.L.A. Documents & Cornell Insurance, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Memorandum of Meeting (1962 Contract Negotiations) Labor Policy Committee (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Containerization Arbitration Award, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- N.Y. Herald Tribune Articles, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- 1962 PWU Negotiations (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 1959 Negotiations (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Longshore Dispute (Atlantic and Gulf Ports), 1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Longshore Dispute (Atlantic and Gulf Ports), 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Chronology: Longshore Dispute, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Final Report: Longshore Dispute, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Background: Longshore Dispute Vol. 2, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Background: Longshore Dispute Vol. 1, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Misc. Documents, Articles, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Vernon H. Jensen, Member Board of Inquiry, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Declaration of Principles; Longshore Industry, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Longshore Dispute, 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- NYSA/ILAS Chronologies and Various Newspaper Articles, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Newspaper Articles, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Articles #2, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Second Report to the President on the Labor Dispute Involving the International Longshoremen's Association and the Maritime Industry on the Atlantic and Gulf Coast, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Misc. Documents and Articles - 1962 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Agreements - 1963 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Agreements - 1963 #2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Agreements - 1963 #3 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Agreements - 1963 #4 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Agreements - 1963 #5 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Agreements and Articles - 1964 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Agreements and Articles - 1964 #2 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Agreements and Articles - 1964 #3 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- 1962-1963 Documents (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Dock Strike - 1964 Folder #1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Articles - 1964 #2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Articles - 1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Articles - 1965 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Articles - 1965 #2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Waterfront Commission of New York Harbor, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- N.Y. Times Articles, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- N.Y. Times Articles - 1967, 1965-1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Meetings and Acts - 1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- The Longshore News, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- N.Y. Times Articles - 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Exhibits 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- International Longshoremen's Association, Independent General Cargo Agreement, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Seniority Board, 1959-1965 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Seniority, 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Dock Strike - 1964 Folder #2 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Negroes - Longshore Bloch, et al., 1961 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Waterfront Commission, 1953-1959 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- NYSA - ILA, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Manpower Utilization - Job Security in the Longshore Industry Folder #1, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Manpower Utilization - Job Security in the Longshpore Industry Folder #2, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Notes, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Charts, Maps and Statistics, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Notes - 1963 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- "To File", 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Rudge Report, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Labor Policy Committee Folder #1, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Labor Policy Committee Folder #2, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Labor Policy Committee Folder #3, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Labor Policy Committee Folder #4, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Labor Policy Committee Folder #5, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- "The Port", 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- News Articles and "Executive Development Program", 1966-1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Port of London Modernisation Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Port of London Modernisation Committee #2, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Booklets, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Misc. Documents; Dock Strike, 1965-1967 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- I.L.A. Hours and Earnings, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Labor Arbitration and Dispute Settlements, 1959-1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Port of New York Longshore Data Book, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Port of New York Labor Relations Committee, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- New York Longshore Industry; Arbitrations and Documents, 1955-1956 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- LRC Report, 1956-1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- NYSA-ILA, 1962-1965 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- NYSA-ILA #2, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- NYSA-ILA #3, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- NYSA-ILA #4, 1956-1958 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Labor Policy Committee and NYSA-ILA, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Decasualization - Economics 10, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Prof. Knight, Mr. Jensen
- Employment Facts - Economics 10, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Wage + Hour Data - Economics 10, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Misc. - Economics 10, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Company, 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Union, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- GM Negotiations 1948 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- W. H. Davis, Speeches at Cornell, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- UAW/GM National Agreement, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Phelps Dodge Corporation, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Memorandum on Taft-Hartley Act, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- N.Y Port/Harbor Books, 1946-1964 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- N.Y. Ports/Harbor Books #2, 1954-1962 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- N.Y. Ports/Harbor Books #3, 1958-1961 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- N.Y. Ports/Harbor #4, 1952-1963 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Industrial Commissioner Corsi's Board of Inquiry (ILA), 1952 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Waterfront Commissions of New York, 1964-1968 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous National and Local Commissions, 1958-1967 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Waterfront, ILA News Articles, 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Booklets on Ports/Harbors, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Hearings Before the Subcommittee on Labor Management Relations, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Unfiled Papers, 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Hatch Gang Directory (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Slightly Burned; Greatly Soiled
- Daily Activity Report; Waterfront Commission New York Harbor, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Hatch Gang Directory: Change Notices, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Information Center Folder #1, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Information Center Folder #2, 1955-1958 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Information Center Folder #3, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Longshore - Expense Account Vouchers - Assignment Recording Sheets, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- W.C. Weekly Statistical Reports of Activity Licensing and Registration Division Initiated, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- W.C. Weekly Report of Operations, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Weekly Report of Operations Licensing Division, 1955-1956 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Weekly Report of Operations Licensing Division #2, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Weekly Report of Operations Licensing Division #3, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Weekly Report of Operations Licensing Division #4, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Weekly Report of Operations Licensing Division, 1958-1961 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Waterfront Commission of N.Y. Harbor, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Waterfront Commission of N.Y. Harbor #2, 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Waterfront Commissioner of N.Y. Harbor, 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Seafarer's Log, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- L'antenne, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Waterfront Commission of N.Y. Harbor, 1956-1958 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Waterfront Commission of New York, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Waterfront Commission of New York Harbor, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- M.P.C., 1951-1952 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- M.P. Catherwood Exhibits, 1951-1952 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Board of Inquiry, 1951-1952 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Appendix Materials, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Crime Commission Hearings - Waterfront, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Bibliography - Longshores, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Longshore - Correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Commissioner Corsi's Fact-Finding Board, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Reports on Foreign Dock Labor, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Contracts Pensions + Organizations Familiar with NY Waterfront, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Recommendations for Improving Labor, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Accidents - Longshore Ind., 1950-1952 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Letters, 1951-1952 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Port of N.Y., 1949-1950 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Labor Relations Committee, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Waterfront Commission of New York Harbor; Regulations, 1953-1956 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- BiState Compact + Regulations, 1953-1955 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Regulation No. 7, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Decasualization, 1956-1958 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Seniority Folder #1, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Seniority Folder #2, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Distribution of Wages, 1956-1958 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Distribution of Wages #2, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Wage + Hour Data - N.Y. Ship. Assoc., 1947-1970 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Customs + Practices "Agreements", 1955 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- NYSA Wage + Hour Data Folder #1, 1949-1952 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- NYSA Wage + Hour Data Folder #2, 1951-1955 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- NYSA Wage + Hour Data Folder #3, 1956-1959 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- NYSA Wage + Hour Data Folder #4, 1959-1963 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Hiring Customs and Practices in the Port of N.Y., 1955 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Customs + Practices Notes, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- WC Data: Employer Data, 1955-1956 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Labor Relations Committee File, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Labor Relations Committee - Meeting, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- LRC - Meetings #2, 1958-1959 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- LRC - Meetings #3, 1957-1958 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- LRC Grievance, 1953-1956 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Pensions, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- NYSA, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Misc. Booklets, Documents, 1955-1957 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Waterfront Commission; Division of Info. Centers, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- NYSA - Reports - Agreements, 1953-1955 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Volume + Steadiness of Employment, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Hiring Practices; Port of N.Y., 1955 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Canada, 1960-1963 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Gang Assignments Folder #1, 1953-1956 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Daily Activity Report Folder #1, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Daily Activity Report Folder #2, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Daily Activity Report Folder #3, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Daily Activity Report Folder #4, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Daily Activity Report Folder #5, 1956-1957 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Daily Activity Reports 1957-1958 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Daily Activity Reports 1958 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Daily Activity Reports - 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Daily Activity Report 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Daily Activity Report 1960 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Daily Activity Report 1961 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Daily Activity Report 1962 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Daily Activity Report 1963 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Daily Activity Report 1964 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Daily Recapitalations, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- NYSA-ILA Seniority Board, 1960-1961 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Gang Turnover, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Various Documents; Longshoremen's Association, Waterfront Commission, 1953-1957 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Releases, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Blank Daily Activity Reports & Disputes Summaries, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Draft Report, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Supporting Chapters, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- M.P.C., 1950 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Regularization of Employment, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Articles & Notes, 1934-1952 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Comparisons of Gang Assignments, 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Statistics - Odds, 1945-1956 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Commerce and Industry Association of N.Y. - News, 1954-1955 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- World Trade Bulletin, 1954-1955 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Code Sheets (Daily Employment), 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Coefficient of Variations (Computations), 1956 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Sums of Scores Squared (Volume Stadiums of Daily Employment), 1957-1958 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Frequency Distributions, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Gang Hiving Data, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Decasualization, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Bibliographical, 1951-1956 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Pier Utilization, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Notes, 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 18)
- Various Letters - ILR, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  English, French, German
- V. H. Jensen Files, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 20)
- The Weekly Averages of Daily Employment, 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 21)
- Seamen's Act; Security of Vessels and Waterfront Facilities, 1952-1955 (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Longshore Labor Market in the Port of N.Y., 1956 (Box 17, Folder 23)
- Memorandums, 1955-1957 (Box 17, Folder 24)
- Notecard References, 1933-1951 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Index Cards (American Steam and Oil Companies), 1936-1941 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Citations - Great Britain, 1924-1931 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Transaction Rate Disadvantages as they Affect the Port of N.Y., 1951 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Records of the Maritime Labor board, 1949-1955 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- The Port of New York Authority Folder #1, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- The Port of New York Authority Folder #2, 1948-1949 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Final Report to Industrial Commissioner, State of New York, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- SIU Handbook, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Longshore Industry Port of N.Y. Strike 1951 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Studies and Reports - Port of N.Y. (Including Crime), 1952 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Decasualization Plans, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 12)
- 1951 Book Stoppage (Box 18, Folder 13)
- New York Shipping Association, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Collective Bargaining + Bank Stoppage, 1951-1952 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Longshoremen Atlantic coast, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 16)
- ILA Procedures, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Report Material, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 18)
- Decasualization West Coast U.S. Experience and Longshoremen, 1948-1952 (Box 18, Folder 19)
- Annual Report Port of Los Angeles & The Port of Vancouver and World Trade, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Mechanization and Modernization, 1960-1963 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Labour Law in the Netherlands Folder #1, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Labour Law in the Netherlands Folders #2, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Labour Law in the Netherlands Folder #3, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Labour Law in the Netherlands Folder #4, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Annual Report Supplement, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Canadian Ports, 1961-1962 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- "Nieuwe Strijd", 1955 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  Dutch
- Reports - Australian Stevedoring Industry Authority Folder #1, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Report - Australian Stevedoring Industry Authority Folder #2, 1960-1962 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Report - Australian Stevedoring Industry Authority Folder #3, 1956-1958 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Report - Australian Stevedoring Industry Authority Folder #4, 1960-1962 (Box 19, Folder 13)
- International Labour Organisation - Inland Transport Committee, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- The Dock and Harbour Authority, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 15)
- NYSA-ILA, 1965-1966 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Australian Stevedoring Industry - Misc. Articles, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Waterfront Commission of New York Harbor, 1959-1960 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- "Is Collective Bargaining Obsolete?" Vernon H. Jensen, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Port of New York Booklets, 1946-1957 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Hearings, 1950-1953 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Hearings #2, 1940-1953 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- U.S. Department of Labor & NYS Legislative Committee, 1932-1943 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- International Labor Review & Handling, Stowage of Cargo, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Industrial Relations in the Various Maritime Industries, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Dock Labour Disputes in Great Britain, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 11)
- ILA, Longshoremen - Misc., 1953 (Box 20, Folder 12)
- N.Y. Longshore Strike; Seaman Merchants, 1951-1959 (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Hearings #3, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 14)
- Vernon H. Jensen - Compilation of Works, 1949-1971 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Pensions - Cbg, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Heritage - Conflict, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Joe Hill, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Nonferrous - Un, 1932-1954 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Hiring - Ports, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Waterfront - N.Y., 1957 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Strife - Docks, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Cbg - Articles, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Computers - Cbg, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Misc. - reviews, 1943 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- 14-B, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 12)
- Technology - Growth, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 13)
- I.L.A. Atlantic Coast District; Quadrennial Convention, 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- The Arbitration Journal, 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- I.L.A. Proceedings of Conventions, 1957-1971 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Memorandum of Meeting (1968 Negotiations) Labor Policy Meeting (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Private File 1969, NYSA-ILA Negotiations (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Memorandum of Meeting (1968 Negotiations) Labor Policy Committee (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Memorandum of Meeting Labor Policy Committee, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Longshore Technology and Hiring, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- ILA Notes and (Map)?, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Newspaper Articles - N.Y. Times, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Private File 1968 - Negotiations (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Misc. Documents, notes, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 12)
- The Settlement, Executive Problems, 1971 Negotiations (Box 22, Folder 13)
- New York Times - 1970 (Box 22, Folder 14)
- The Assessment Committee Unanimous Recommendation, 1970-1971 (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Notes - ILA, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 16)
- N.Y. Times - Articles, 1967-1969 (Box 22, Folder 17)
- American Labor and Maritime Reporter and Engineering News, 1967-1969 (Box 22, Folder 18)
- Various Newspaper Articles - Longshore Industry, 1969-1970 (Box 22, Folder 19)
- ILA Negotiations - Federal Pay Board, 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 20)
- East and Gulf Coast; Longshore, 1971-1972 (Box 22, Folder 21)
- Impact of Longshore Strikes on the National Economy, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 22)
- "The Times" - 1972 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- "The Times" - 1972 #2 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- "The Times" - 1972 #3 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- The Port; An Independent Port Newspaper, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- The Port, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- The Port #2, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Decision of U.S. Supreme Court; Bay Ridge Operating Co., Inc., and "The Times" Articles, 1947-1972 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Notes and Newspaper Articles "The Times", 1970 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Enclosed Docks Productivity Agreement, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- "The Port" - Union Warn on Non-Dock Labour, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Realities of Labor Relations in the Port Industry, 1955-1970 (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Modernisation Committee's, 1968-1970 (Box 23, Folder 12)
- London Port Documents, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 13)
- London Port Documents #2, 1967-1970 (Box 23, Folder 14)
- ILWU Newsletters, 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 15)